[MUSIC]
[음악]
Build a sentiment classifier.
감성 분류기 만들기
And I'm gonna put a # here to make it a nice title.
#를 붙여서 제목으로 만들겠습니다
So this is our next task here.
이게 다음 작업으로 넘어가죠
And so, when you build a sentiment classifier,
감성 분류기를 만들 때
you're talking about positives and negatives.
긍정, 부정을 다루게 되죠
So, thumbs down, and thumbs up.
강추나, 비추냐
But if you remember, our product ratings, we're not about positive and
상품 평점은 긍정, 부정이 아니라
negative, they're numerical things.
그저 숫자일 뿐입니다
So, for example, if I take all the products, and
예를 들어 모든 상품의 평점 열에
I'll take the rating column and I do a .show, and we did above just for
기린에게 했듯이 카테고리가 일치하는
the giraffe, but do a .show for everything with the view equal
모든 열에 .show를 붙이면
to Categorical, we're now getting a histogram for
모든 뷰에 대한 히스토그램이 나오고,
all of the views, and if you take a quick look at it, you'll see that most reviews
잠깐 살펴보면 거의 모든 리뷰가 긍정적으로
are positive across the board 107,000 reviews are five stars.
107000개의 리뷰가 5점입니다
So most people review positively, and just write reviews about products they like.
대부분의 사람은 좋아하는 상품에 대한 긍정적인 리뷰를 남깁니다
They don't typically write reviews about products they don't like.
좋아하지 않는 상품에 대해서는 보통 안 쓰죠
Then the next set of reviews, 33,000 four stars.
다음으론 4점이 33000개 있습니다
Then 3 stars and again, a lot of people write really bad reviews 1 star, 2 star,
그리고 3점, 그리고 낮은 1점, 2점
why would you give a review product 2 stars?
대체 왜 2점을 줄까요?
You might as well just give them 1 star if you really hated it.
그렇게 싫으면 차라리 1점을 주지요
And this is what we observe in the histogram.
지금까지 히스토그램을 살펴봤습니다
But again, for sentiment analysis, we have to define what's thumbs up and
감성분석을 위해선
what's thumbs down.
강추와 비추를 구분해야 합니다
And so I'm gonna make an arbitrary choice here.
일단 아무렇게나 해봅니다
Let's say that things that 4, 5 stars are things that people liked.
4,5점은 사람들이 좋아하는
So those are positives.
긍정적인 리뷰라고 가정합니다
Things that 1 and 2 stars are negative.
1,2점은 부정적이고요
But the things that are 3 stars, those are kind of in the middle.
3점은 중간입니다
So, let's just throw those out.
그냥 버립시다
So we're gonna do a little bit of what we'll call data engineering,
데이터 공학이라는 걸 조금 할 텐데
just defining what is a positive and negative sentiment.
어떤 게 긍정적이고 부정적인지 밝히는 작업입니다
So let's do that right now.
바로 해보죠
So in the subsection we're gonna define
부제로 긍정적, 부정적 감성
what's a positive and a negative sentiment.
구분하기라고 씁니다
And what I'm gonna
먼저
do first is ignore all
별점 3개 리뷰를
city star reviews.
전부 무시합니다
The way to do it is by saying,
그러려면
okay I'm gonna take the product stable the variable products.
상품 변수 표에서
And I'm gonna just select everything out
별점 3개가 아닌 것만
of the products table whose rating was not 3.
선택합니다
So, products[products['rating'] |= 3].
products[products['rating'] != 3] 이렇게 하죠
So that was our first step in our little data engineering task.
데이터 공학을 위한 첫걸음을 디뎠습니다
And now, the next step in this task
다음으로
is to actually find what stems up and stems down.
강추와 비추를 구분합니다
So I'm gonna say a positive
긍정적 감성은
sentiment equals 4 star or
별점이 4,5개인
5 star reviews.
리뷰입니다
So let's go ahead and
이제 딥 특징이
add a new column to our table that defines the actual sentiment.
표에 새로운 감성 열을 추가해 줍니다
So products new column called sentiment.
상품의 새 열인 감성은
It's gonna be a binary column, zero one.
0이나 1인 이진 열이 될 겁니다
And, the way we're gonna define the column, is we're gonna say,
그러기 위해 열에
of the products rating, is it greater equal to 4?
상품 평점이 4보다 크거나 같으면
If it's greater or equal to 4, it's gonna get a 1, and
1을 넣고 아니면
if it's less than 4, it's gonna get a 0, and
0을 넣습니다
so now if I take another look at my product stable, so head
이제 상품 표 헤드를 보면
You should see that I've added a new column on the right called Sentiment.
감성이란 열이 오른쪽에 추가되어 있습니다
And most of the sentiments are positive, as we saw earlier, but
감성은 대부분 긍정적이지만
many are negative, zero.
몇몇은 부정적입니다
Okay, now we're ready, we're finally
이제 준비를 마쳤으니
ready to train our sentiment classifier.
감성 분류기를 훈련시킬 차례입니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]